{
  "LANGHINDI": 17,
  "qu1": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>\r\n\tThe headstock of a lathe has 9 speeds with minimum speed of 100 rpm and maximum speed of 1600 rpm. If the speeds are in geometric progression, then step ratio is</p>",
      "OPT1": "1.06",
      "OPT2": "1.22",
      "OPT3": "1.41",
      "OPT4": "1.64",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "9m/iwvJKC6coEJr5HJJczQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "9m/iwvJKC6coEJr5HJJczQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0",
      "OPT2": "\u00a0",
      "OPT3": "\u00a0",
      "OPT4": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13298796",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18438864",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "7",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "MECHANICAL ENGINEERING",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "1.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.33",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu2": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>\r\n\tA side and face cutter 125 mm in diameter has 10 teeth. It operates at a cutting speed of 31.4 m/min with table traverse of 100 mm/min. The feed per tooth of cutter is</p>",
      "OPT1": "10 mm",
      "OPT2": "0.25 mm",
      "OPT3": "0.85 mm",
      "OPT4": "0.125 mm",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "Wkw/v0ACIC+JhZVbmq0HcA==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "Wkw/v0ACIC+JhZVbmq0HcA==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0",
      "OPT2": "\u00a0",
      "OPT3": "\u00a0",
      "OPT4": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13298796",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18438864",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "7",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "MECHANICAL ENGINEERING",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "1.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.33",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu3": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>\r\n\tIn an abrasive jet machining, the total material removal rate for flow rate \u2018<em>Q</em>\u2019 of abrasives and the mean diameter \u2018<em>d</em>\u2019 of the abrasive is 16 mm3/s. If the flow rate of abrasives is tripled and the mean diameter of the abrasives is halved, then the MRR will be</p>",
      "OPT1": "<p>\r\n\t12 mm<sup>3</sup>/s</p>",
      "OPT2": "<p>\r\n\t6 mm<sup>3</sup>/s</p>",
      "OPT3": "<p>\r\n\t32 mm<sup>3</sup>/s</p>",
      "OPT4": "<p>\r\n\t20 mm<sup>3</sup>/s</p>",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "fhPK/WKkcuYMengj9uY6cg==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "fhPK/WKkcuYMengj9uY6cg==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0",
      "OPT2": "\u00a0",
      "OPT3": "\u00a0",
      "OPT4": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13298796",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18438864",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "7",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "MECHANICAL ENGINEERING",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "1.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.33",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu4": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>\r\n\t3 - 2 - 1 method of location in a jig or fixture would collectively restrict the workpiece in</p>",
      "OPT1": "6 degrees of freedom",
      "OPT2": "8 degrees of freedom",
      "OPT3": "9 degrees of freedom",
      "OPT4": "12 degrees of freedom",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "9m/iwvJKC6coEJr5HJJczQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "9m/iwvJKC6coEJr5HJJczQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0",
      "OPT2": "\u00a0",
      "OPT3": "\u00a0",
      "OPT4": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13298796",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18438864",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "7",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "MECHANICAL ENGINEERING",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "1.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.33",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu5": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>\r\n\tThe direction of movement of chips during machining using a single point cutting tool is governed by</p>",
      "OPT1": "side rake angle",
      "OPT2": "back rake angle",
      "OPT3": "side cutting edge angle",
      "OPT4": "side relief angle",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "fhPK/WKkcuYMengj9uY6cg==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "fhPK/WKkcuYMengj9uY6cg==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0",
      "OPT2": "\u00a0",
      "OPT3": "\u00a0",
      "OPT4": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13298796",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18438864",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "7",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "MECHANICAL ENGINEERING",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "1.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.33",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu6": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>\r\n\tAn orthogonal turning operation carried out at a cutting speed of 25 m/min using a cutting tool of rake angle 10\u00b0. If the cut and uncut chip thickness are 0.4 mm and 0.2 mm respectively, the chip velocity will be ____ m/min. (Correct upto 1 decimal place)</p>",
      "OPT1": "12.5 (12.5 - 12.5)",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "LvXz75g6a4xiQk+X0/XgumNTQb2kqCON3kpovtOu8L4=",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": " ",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "5kxMa8YwwyHwJY15nzG3sQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13298796",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18438864",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "2",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "Alphanumeric",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "MECHANICAL ENGINEERING",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "1.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.00",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0"
  },
  "qu7": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>\r\n\tIn a machining operation with a tool having back rake angle as 10\u00b0, the chip thickness ratio was observed as 0.3. In this operation, the shear strain observed will be ______. (Correct upto 2 decimal places)</p>",
      "OPT1": "3.34 (3.30 - 3.39)",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "A6tquBbqHcj+vY7wQk4GmiKQYjARt9+ehIUKe+0tTo4=",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "5kxMa8YwwyHwJY15nzG3sQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13298796",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18438864",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "2",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "Alphanumeric",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "MECHANICAL ENGINEERING",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "1.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.00",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu8": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>\r\n\tIf the shaper tool has a stroke length of 240 mm and number of double strokes per minute is 40 and ratio of return to cutting time is 2 : 3, then its cutting speed is _____ m/min (Answer in integer)</p>",
      "OPT1": "16 (16 - 16)",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "YkOVKfc6/Qp4xmBHXD9iEQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "5kxMa8YwwyHwJY15nzG3sQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13298796",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18438864",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "2",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "Alphanumeric",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "MECHANICAL ENGINEERING",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "1.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.00",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu9": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>\r\n\tThe self sharpening tendency of a conventional grinding wheel does not depend on</p>",
      "OPT1": "wheel structure",
      "OPT2": "wheel grade",
      "OPT3": "grit hardness",
      "OPT4": "grit size",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "fUwGNpwrpUE3GIKhfsyzGA==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "fUwGNpwrpUE3GIKhfsyzGA==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0",
      "OPT2": "\u00a0",
      "OPT3": "\u00a0",
      "OPT4": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13298796",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18438864",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "5",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "MECHANICAL ENGINEERING",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "1.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.00",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu10": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>\r\n\tA researcher conducts ECM on a binary alloy of density 6000 kg/m<sup>3</sup> of iron with atomic weight 56 and valency 2 and metal <em>X</em> of atomic weight 24 and valency 4. The volumetric material removal rate of the alloy is 50 mm<sup>3</sup>/s at a current of 2000A. What is the percentage of metal <em>X</em> in the alloy?</p>",
      "OPT1": "74.5%",
      "OPT2": "25.5%",
      "OPT3": "30.1%",
      "OPT4": "69.9%",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "fhPK/WKkcuYMengj9uY6cg==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "fhPK/WKkcuYMengj9uY6cg==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0",
      "OPT2": "\u00a0",
      "OPT3": "\u00a0",
      "OPT4": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13298796",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18438864",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "7",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "MECHANICAL ENGINEERING",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "2.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.66",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu11": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>\r\n\tA rod of length 600 mm and diameter 80 mm is turned using HSS tool. For this machining operation the Taylor\u2019s tool life parameters are 0.2 and 120. If the tool change time and machining time are 8 min and 12 min respectively, the cutting speed which will yield maximum production rate will be</p>",
      "OPT1": "52.91 m/min",
      "OPT2": "55.32 m/min",
      "OPT3": "57.38 m/min",
      "OPT4": "60.00 m/min",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "Wkw/v0ACIC+JhZVbmq0HcA==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "Wkw/v0ACIC+JhZVbmq0HcA==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0",
      "OPT2": "\u00a0",
      "OPT3": "\u00a0",
      "OPT4": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13298796",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18438864",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "7",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "MECHANICAL ENGINEERING",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "2.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.66",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu12": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>\r\n\tIn an orthogonal cutting operation, a tool with ORS signature, 0 - 10 - 7 - 7 - 10 - 75 - 1 is used.<br />\r\n\tGiven that, width of cut = 3.6 mm<br />\r\n\tShear strength of workpiece material = 460 N/mm<sup>2</sup><br />\r\n\tDepth of cut = 0.25 mm<br />\r\n\tCoefficient of friction at chip-tool interface = 0.7<br />\r\n\tFor minimum cutting force, the shear plane angle will be _____ degrees. (Correct upto 1 decimal place)</p>",
      "OPT1": "32.5",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "jF3qDggC4jzlois0iQA9Qw==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "5kxMa8YwwyHwJY15nzG3sQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13298796",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18438864",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "2",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "Alphanumeric",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "MECHANICAL ENGINEERING",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "2.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.00",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu13": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>\r\n\tFifty flat pieces of 1 mm thickness and initial dimensions as shown in figure A is to be milled in a single cut to the final dimensions as shown in figure B. The cutter has a diameter of 25 mm and has 10 teeth and rotates at 100 rpm. Horizontal feed of the table is 10 mm/min. Assuming single tooth in contact, the material removal rate will be</p>\r\n<p>\r\n\t<img alt=\"\" src=\"data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAoAAAAB/CAYAAAB/lnPGAAAc+klEQVR4Xu2dfXRU5Z3Hv+W4Hg8npa2lXRRfWm3kWKi1QHrQupK0uIeWNbzVVjSFgCIihigpqRA0REnApLyDtKZA4klFaoEQilKKB+wLxQVsd1fWE1NbPBWNXaluNmvdls3uc+/MxEkyyczce2fmzsxn/mmHzPP2eX7z7fd5fr87/dD/mZd4QQACEIAABCAAAQhkDYEPYQCzZq9ZKAQgAAEIQAACELAJYAAJBAhAAAIQgAAEIJBlBDCAWbbhLBcCEIAABCAAAQhgAIkBCEAAAhCAAAQgkGUEXBnATw0flmW4WC4E0p/A6TPtURfh5rsdS/9RJ8AHIAABCEAgoQRcG8DDvzya0AnSOQQg4B2Bghuul1uDFjKHbvvxblX0BAEIQAAC8RLAAMZLjM9DII0JYADTePOYOgQgAAEPCWAAPYRJVxDwOwG3BjA8NZyJN4BuUt9+33vmB4FMJhBNj9x+t6P1n45sMYDpuGvMGQIOCWAABwZn/Y8EZS0Og4tmEEgRAa90LRNN3kBbggFMUcAyLARSQcArobTmnoliiQFMRVQyJgTcEfBK1zJR0zCA7mKL1hDIGAJeCWUISKYJJgYwY0KdhWQRAa90LdP0LFoIcAMYjRB/h0AGEXAjlJFqaDJNMDGAGRTsLCVrCHipa5mmadwAZs3XgIVCYGACXgplJqaBMYB8gyCQfgS81DUMYIz7j1jGCIqPQcAnBNwIZWgJmfw7gGiaTwKVaUAgDgJudK13ZgMDGCN4xDJGUHwMAj4h4EYoMYA+2USmAQEI9CDgVNeyoayFFDBfFghAwCbgVCjD8XEDSDBBAAJ+IuBU1/r7bcBsuQXkIRA/RTFzgUCCCTgVSgxggjeG7iEAAccE3OpaJh9quQF0HFY0hEBmEXArlBaNTBZLyloyK95ZTXYQcKtrmaxpGMDs+A6wSghEJeBWKDGAURHzAQhAIMkE3OoaBtDBhnFadgCNJhBIIQG3QokBTOHmMTQEIBCRgFtdwwA6CCwMoANoNIFACgm4FUoMYAo3j6EhAAEMoIcxwEMgHsKkKwj4nQAGcOAd4lDr9whmfhDoS8CtrnED6CCqEEsH0GgCgRQScCuU3ACmcPMYGgIQ4AbQwxjgBtBDmHQFAb8TwAByA+j3GGV+EIiXgFtd4wYwXuLm89wAOoBGEwikkIBboeQGMIWbx9AQgAA3gB7GADeAHsKkKwj4nQAGkBtAv8co84NAvATc6ho3gPES5wbQATGaQCC1BNwKJTeAqd0/RocABPoScKtrGEAHUUUK2AE0mkAghQTcCiUGMIWbx9AQgEBEAm51DQPoILAwgA6g0QQCKSTgVigxgCncPIaGAAQwgB7GADWAHsKkKwj4nQAGcOAd4lDr9whmfhAgBexVDGAAvSJJPxBIAwJeGMA0WKbjKWIAHaOjIQRSRsCtrpECdrB1iKUDaDSBQAoJuBXKFE49KUOjaUnBzCAQ8JQAuuYMJzeAzrjRCgJpSQChJAWcloHLpCEwAAF0zVl4YACdcaMVBNKSAEKJAUzLwGXSEMAAeh4DGEDPkdIhBPxLIKIB7HpTxzdWaFbtM3pPl2hC+QatKLlewwZJXe1HtaliodYceF3K+ZoWNVXr3ryLZP6UkS9SwBm5rSwqwwlwsHW2wRhAZ9xoBYG0JNBXKM+pvXmplr02xZi+sdLztZpd9IzGNLVoxfizapg8XTsLtuvpRSN0pmGxplZ0qPzIdhXnXpCW6482aQxgNEL8HQL+I9CvAexs03OPr1TJautwm6OrZ9Vpw9LJys3pMrpXqnELdoUtZqgmbH5WP5hyqf8WmKAZYQATBJZuIeBHAn2FslMvrt+qjtklyh9i7vXa9+jOMT/SDcbkzdQOTc0/qKkhw9dxWMvyStT+aOaKJAbQj1HLnCAwMIHIBjB4uH13ptYVf1ZqbdJ9heU6On2HjtX8g95rrtaOS8t0/5icrMWLAczarWfh2Uhg4FRJh1obqrROs1VnBLPrcKXGFf1ZNSfXa8qw86RzJ7V29CQ9UbxfxxeNkfmXwMucso/8dJ92HnxPV5xr1maTLh48sVZ7qq/VryvmaLn9vlKN1Xcoz/TT2fYLHdy3Sz8790n9besmHeo0aefqbVpx3W+1zAi0/T4sDZ3MfcIAJpM2Y0HAGwKRde19tTU8plMTFwb0S+awu2aapp2ar2Nbb5YwgMIAehN/9AKBtCDQnwE8d3KN8gpr9Y69irEq2rxKs7RFNy2Q1g1kAIOmcP1Z02zUEu3eVaJrO/ZqQcF8PX+DMYHrb9Pw1s26pbBew0165XuXPh0cx6RjynaY1PLn1dH8bU1YcFTXVzeYk/olemVNsaatHv7BuEkkiwFMImyGgoBHBGKrAXxbR5YW6h5VB28Al2rJvtN64cDPe6WHwyqcM+hwGwk1BtCjAKQbCKQDgahC2fWGjlTepeJtf6+Fi6QNay7oZQBn6dTDvVLAXa2mVnCS1hfsDNwM9r4ptN9/0K6rbbtJLe9QfstuO/0SMJ8HNLPH+1dVGTKeSQSLAUwibIaCgEcEouqaNY5VwnLDHo098F1NudjKRBzVCV2jfFPP3H58q5YVrdaZedahNM9UC5pXhh1uMYAeBRvdQCBdCfQRSsu8LXxBX9owU7nBg69tyG57R7WPfVjlM3+j0h41gBXS98wDIgVDwxD8Uc13fFVVIxtjMoCBOsMtGokBTNcwYt4Q8BWBqAbQPthW6/CXK1RZcHGEXzEI3A4Wv7XYpIenalhodRl0uMUA+ipkmQwEkk8g4kMga+bosQsfMunXUcrpbFVzzXL95KoKrfv6X1Q/fbYOfnGdtlfdqK4Wk6rdcqWaTJp3dE5YmiSDRJIbwOTHJCNCwC2B6LXNa7Xz8rlaFjJ/na/qxTc/odG5Q4JDh6eHCxT6VylzDrcYQLdRRnsIpDmBvkLZpc6TG02N3kq9bK1tlHlo44HZ+npBrkmDmL+17dWqexer6aVO87e5WrdpsaZ0i2avNIl5+7GSct36ZK22WDWB1vsy88DInR1anjdDTaaLnq9rNL9srJ5avS1Ye3iNSlt+rDs66szDJ/WmLsd6H0gTJ+uFAUwWacaBgHcE+jWA9m+crtS2j9xlHmwzB9zQkFY6+PZfaUJ9ufLNdZ+dAn74rIrs9+d/MLEMOtxiAL2LN3qCQFoSiJoqSctVeTdpDKB3LOkJAskiEPkH7kP1zCf6HDxLW57SN/+43Dx89qPgAyBVql54i0aHm7/wGsAMONxiAJMVjYwDAZ8SwAAOvDEYQJ8GLtOCwAAE0DVn4cFTwM640QoCaUkAocQApmXgMmkIYAA9jwEMoOdI6RAC/iWAAcQA+jc6mRkEnBFA15xxwwA640YrCKQlAYQSA5iWgcukIcANoOcxgAH0HCkdQsC/BLwwgFadnPU6fabdvwt1ODNqAB2CoxkEUkjAC11L4fRTNjQGMGXoGRgCySfghVBiAJO/b4wIAQj0T8CtrmWypg0UNxhAvlUQyCICboXSQpXJYskNYBZ9GVhqxhBwq2uZrGkYwIwJcxYCAXcE3AolBtAdf1pDAALeE3CraxhAB3vCadkBNJpAIIUE3AolBjCFm8fQEIBARAJudQ0D6CCwMIAOoNEEAikk4FYoMYAp3DyGhgAEMIAexgA1gB7CpCsI+J0ABnDgHeJQ6/cIZn4Q6EvAra5xA+ggqhBLB9BoAoEUEnArlNwApnDzGBoCEOAG0MMY4AbQQ5h0BQG/E8AAcgPo9xhlfhCIl4BbXeMGMF7i5vPcADqARhMIpJCAW6HkBjCFm8fQEIAAN4AexgA3gB7CpCsI+J0ABpAbQL/HKPODQLwE3OoaN4DxEucG0AExmkAgtQTcCiU3gKndP0aHAAT6EnCraxhAB1FFCtgBNJpAIIUE3AolBjCFm8fQEIBARAJudQ0D6CCwMIAOoNEEAikk4FYoMYAp3DyGhgAEMIAexgA1gB7CpCsI+J0ABnDgHeJQ6/cIZn4QIAXsVQxgAL0iST8QSAMCGEAMYBqEKVOEQFwE3OoaKeC4cAc+zGnZATSaQCCFBNwKZeh7b/3n6TPtKVxJYoZG0xLDlV4hkEgCbnUNA+hgdxBLB9BoAoEUEnArlBjAFG4eQ0MAAhEJuNU1DKCDwMIAOoBGEwikkIBbocQApnDzGBoCEMAAehgD1AB6CJOuIOB3Am4MYOiUHL7GTEsDc6j1ewQzPwj0JeBU1yJpmtV7pulafzGDAeTbBIEsIuBUKMNv/jCAWRQwLBUCaUDAqa5lw6F2oO3DAKZBcDNFCHhFwKlQYgC92gH6gQAEvCbgpa5ly+2ftQcYQK8jkf4g4GMCboQykgnMNLEkBezj4GVqEOiHgBtd630LmGmaxg0gXxsIQMAm4EYoexvATBRKDCBfFAikHwE3uoYBdLjfiKVDcDSDQIoIuBFKDGCKNo1hIQCBAQl4pWuZeKjlBpAvDwQgwA1gDDHAoTYGSHwEAj4jgAF0tiHUADrjRisIpCUBt0IZfguYiadlDGBahjWTznICbnWNH4J2EED9/YaOg65oAgEIJIlALMbNzXc7lv6TtNS4h3Gz7rgHowEEIOAZgWi64/a7Ha1/zxaSxI5c3QAmcZ4MBQEIQAACEIAABCDgEQEMoEcg6QYCEIAABCAAAQikCwEMYLrsFPOEAAQgAAEIQAACHhHAAHoEkm4gAAEIQAACEIBAuhDAAKbLTjFPCEAAAhCAAAQg4BEBVwbQeqomE5+M8Ygt3UDAdwT4zg68JfDxXcgyIQhEJcD3NiqiiB/AADrj5o9WnW167vGVKln9jN5Tjq6eVacNSycrN2eQ1PWmjm+s0Kxa62+XaEL5Bq0ouV7D/rRHd46Zr0PhK5i4Rce2TtUwf6yKWSSQAEKJAUxgeHnQdZc62w6pftVSrT/wuulvrIo2r9YDU0YYhTOy1n5UmyoWao31t5yvaVFTte7N+4T+1FyqcQt2hY0/VBM2P6sfTLnUgznRhd8JoGvOdggD6IybD1qdU3vzUi17d6bWFX9Wam3SfYXlOjp9h47VXKe3Gmbrph3jtHvXAl115knzt4f1H0v2a8/Ef1fpk5dp7aIxOs8Hq2AKySWAUGIAkxtx8Y72RzXPq9O7i1aoeISRtYbFmlrxb5rW1KIV48+qYfJ07SzYrqcXjdAZ+28dKj9Sr4mnVmvHpWW6f4xlE3llGwF0zdmOJ9QAsinONiW2Vu+rreExnZq4UFOGWVauUy+umaZpp+brWP1ndcAI5Z7pu7THqOggva0jSwtV/NZiHauWqjGAsSFOw09F+85F+3saLtnTKcfCJ5bPeDqpbOqsq1UNla2a+EhhICNx7qTWjp6lUw8/q8dHHtLU/IOaemS7inMvkDoOa1leidof3acVegIDmE1x0mutfCedbb6nBjDSL21TI+hsY+JvFTB596haxx6Qam1hDKVAguawYaJ27/+06pft0/vHntHhTjPKqLlat2mxpuQOCRvSSsP8Qgf37dLPzn1Sf9u6SYc6TRq5eptWXPdbLTM3jfb7UFp5UIfaDh/QT576pc5d2ant603aOWeylrcs03W/XmFO6XvN+1C65iJjSHklikC07yBCGf8NYDSmidpL+jUEbJNXIX2vWeXaqHFFf1bNyfWBQ69tDifpieK92nfFLj2477ReOPDzvuUw3SDj1ClTYnPkp/u08+B7uuJcszabtPPgibXaU32tfl0xR8vt95VqrL5DecPOZ7sSRCCW7x+65gy+awPobFhahRPwxCRbQnnDHo098F1NGbTf1Pk9KHXXwIQZwJ/frI7fmMqaglwNDtXTvP4tkyou0WirdtA+dK9RXmGt3rHqCst2mHTL59XR/G1NWHBU11c3mJTzJXplTbGmrR6udSerddmT3zD//V9Ny3EqbWnQ/V/4TzXPn677jowxJrBOxcNbtXb6DK2/pM5VraHb/ysfoi5AwJN4y1CYxJg3G+tNjHUZ/1ep8U+N1v4tN2tQi1XnJ6M5vQ3gPh2++X/0W12jfHMz2H58q5YVrdaZeZZ25dm1g90Zklh16vuXaYcxl+vPWofkJbY+XtuxVwsK5uv5G4wJXH+bhrdu1i2F9RrustaQmPNTzHkzl3TpBQPog51yLZZdb+hIZbUOf7lClQUXa1C79aBHBANopYd7POwRENgep+ogj6627SbdskP5LbvtupqAKTygmT3ev6pKW4zPmXS0qTlck6fdLy7S6PPCDGf4+z7jxwcfoYyPV3+fdh1v3kzDl70QY95sixcx1tV+SFUVx1VQXab8YYNMzXMkAxhID/d82COs5KWH3lllM3HolJWOnmxMYMFOHbdqprtvHPeHvY80fnwMibn4eKFr3vCyenFtAMO/6LFc1Xo3dXoKEOgwhdJrtfPyuVpmmT/rn2yh+qaOLDIPfYTVAN6jMjVOv1ZXj7kyeCoOGsC7pceOVyl/SFhy1jaRWzQyJgOogDg/dGVCDSA7Hp1AtO8gqZKBGfbm09//OHthcKLvZhZ/ovMlNdQc1KcW3mvMXyC9GjiEHldpjxpAkx5+dLWmjRyp0d1lLGHlMDUF+qC4xXpwLh6dMg+k3PFVVY1sTKgBzOJdjmnpsXwH0bWYUPb5kKcGMLz30KYhlM42JqZW9k+9rNS2j9yluuJRQVNntXzXPBBiUrQ/HauGxnLd2LXfpC4addWTdfrCrkd0+KZV9k2h7BTwRp016RL75jBsUD/eAMbEJMs/FO17h1DGZwB7fzoa3ywPP0+Wb//US+UuDVlUaZ4EDqtN7jxuSklm6+AX12l71Y3qajFlKVuuVNP2kdo975gm1Jcbs2hkzUoBP3xWRfb78No8f94AegItgzuJ5TuHrjkLgIQZQGfToVXMBOy0710q3naiV5NrTB2eSduOOKPmmjLd12j9/YPf0hr8xh67juVZ+wGQOXqkpkS3j+n5YMYHNYBW19doftlYPbV6m6kJDLwvbfmx7uioM6njelNw3ev18Tkqve2E1m+0agLN6+Pl5lZwpjoeMk8hN/4++N5KE8e8Uj7oIQGE0p0B9HAr6CoCATvtO+tuNb5kCVTYy9aR+3TVH/Zq1b2L1WT9vfsBtgv0hl2j/KPgAyBVql54i0b3MH/BshS7BtDSpSg61WtuHysp161P1mqLVRNoXh8rM2ngOzu0PG+GmsxU7Pf8tFbKYhpdc4YeA+iMG60gkJYEEEoMYFoGLpOGwAAE0DVn4YEBdMaNVhBISwIIJQYwLQOXSUMAA+h5DLgygJ7Phg4hAAEIQAACEIAABBJOAAOYcMQMAAEIQAACEIAABPxFAAPor/1gNhCAAAQgAAEIQCDhBDCACUfMABCAAAQgAAEIQMBfBDCA/toPZgMBCEAAAhCAAAQSTgADmHDEDAABCEAAAhCAAAT8RQAD6K/9YDYQgAAEIAABCEAg4QQwgAlHzAAQgAAEIAABCEDAXwQwgP7aD2YDAQhAAAIQgAAEEk4AA5hwxAwAAQhAAAIQgAAE/EUAA+iv/WA2EIAABCAAAQhAIOEEMIAJR8wAEIAABCAAAQhAwF8EMID+2g9mAwEIQAACEIAABBJOAAOYcMQMAAEIQAACEIAABPxFAAPor/1gNhCAAAQgAAEIQCDhBDCACUfMABCAAAQgAAEIQMBfBDCA/tqPOGfTpY7DlRpXVK/3+rS8QkVNLVqR9wetnV4n1Tyu+8d8NM7+E/TxrlY1TL5bv1v0tFYUDE3QIHQLAQikH4EYNK3gPL245i5VaLGeXpSnnJQs8m0dWVqo4sbf9xo9R1fPqtOGpZOVmzMoJTNjUAjESgADGCspP3+u47CW5c1Q01Ur9bO9s5U7yBLR72q15qjKdwawS50nN+qWwpV6bdYOHasp0BA/s2VuEIBA8gkMpGm+MIAWkvfV1jBbN1W8FjhsFwzRG83f1oQFzyi3er/2FI8QFjD5ocOIsRPAAMbOyr+fDIrl7unpYKisk3OJmt46q0MHPq7lR7arOPcC/7JlZhCAQPIJpIWmhW4rn9M02wAOVVfbdk3Nr5YwgMmPGUaMmwAGMG5kPmzQWyzN+8q6/9XcLz+vf7TTw8F0sJ1u7VDbc9v16D0rdahTGjyxVnvWF2nE4DaTlp2k5S+af8yZq4ZD43VoQpGazFuNNjeLe67Xr6YG/j54YrmqRr6kmre/pedrxmtQ2yHVr1qq9Qdel0bN1bpNizUlN/K9Xtcbe1S65aN6ZOZpzTJC+deyHSlM4/hwL5kSBCBgZCqQ1eg+1NqaJpUtlmqtbIelXd0ZBJNVCNegnMla3lJnDpZvDqxpe2dIT1g3eIeN5n1NpY+M0qkV76jol1XKH/Sqnnt8pUpWP2P0c6yKNq/WA1NG9Eo39zaA56u1YbFu/cWX9JSlqaSAiWSfE8AA+nyDYppeKF1imbXgKyCO4yW7RrD3CXWzLt68S5sL39cT4abvhRk6/a1CLX9lhhqOV+nGtxrNaXaJ2kJCGxrnU0u0e9c8XdL5ni78r72anl+vz1kn4PFnA4JrqnMCqejes7dSJmVqvLzKnJYVqKHZ9RV7rPwhJEti2ms+BIFsINCvppmSkd7m0K4pnqTai+t0aMtX9d8hU2cdfJ9Ypc+sm9O/pilUy/dJlbY0qPTSv+jtCzv0jDns1n6u3mjodXrLTvMqQraid72iVf+3RPOuu1bjJo3RMCQtGyI1rdeIAUzr7QtOvr/T8iO9DeCFwYdGdgRqVGaaA7Bl2IKGLz8neAsYeq/n+5zCe9YahmpgzAk6/GXdIEYydZZQL3xBX9owM1inaJnTZzXeMqNTLqdeJhNikTVAwAsC/WpaBAPYo14wdKsXrMsLHUr707RuA3h5t8ELpHGX6F96rCM8ixL6Q+8bwAvV2dqk+wof1pl5ZDa8CAP6SCwBDGBi+San9z4F0/0JlEkBd72pF3+4URUPbNPL1sdGzdEjNSW6fcxFGhQ8SUe9Aex+2KR3EfRAT/QO8HSflWKOeGOYHHyMAgEI+IxAv5pm5tmnPvCvaj/5tDYtrVTTS1YaxKRsV1Xq3tvzNEyB28F+NW0AA9id+egXTd8aQIU0tN8siM84M52sJoABzITtj8sAvqbm+Qt04taGvj/B0sMAVmps2+aeT+tGGCd0Wm4L1RLmnFN725vKyb28Z71Mlxm38oAu+85cje6ujflr8Km5E91F1JmwHawBAhBwSSBOA2g9fTvpn6eamuRevyoQTdMiGMBuE/fKVwK1hCOGqKv9VZ3O+bSu6FHX1/cp4PbjW7WsaKv+7lGyGi4jgOZJIIABTALkxA0R4VatO/1qHZTDfyOwIJDiuOh3aigt1nLrgY2w1+B/2mLqZyZp0PO1ml20SS+bQuqHaq7U3oVr7FTI4NvLNPvl72uz9ZCI9eq+tTOnb1v0quyHSnrcKIb6D4mw1Tbstq9nqiVSiiVx5OgZAhDwI4GBNM0U1fWoDczR5+2nbS8ytcWLNbVib8/fQ835htYdrtG41nWRNW3WVjVe1aRbrIdA7FdQI82vEnS1H9WmioVaY+tk2I1ieF1fhDpF+2GSRxdoRiE1gH6MLubUkwAGMKsiwjwtZ2pUFm/8sB7cMFUX22IWPMWu/AwPY2RVLLBYCGQIgc6X1FD2pD5auVxTLj7fXlTgcBl8OI0fm8+QjWYZXhPAAHpN1Nf9BZ54u+etuwM//WKlMzpb1VzzHX1/aAU/x+LrvWNyEIBAXwLBG8O7/6TyYLrW/qmr5jot3DJU1btKwkpO4AcBCIQTwABmWTx0tR/XDzdU6cHGE4GVk7LIsghguRDIMAK9H2zTJZpQVqF7bpuk0cMCN4K8IACBvgQwgEQFBCAAAQhAAAIQyDICGMAs23CWCwEIQAACEIAABDCAxAAEIAABCEAAAhDIMgIYwCzbcJYLAQhAAAIQgAAEMIDEAAQgAAEIQAACEMgyAv8P2e/cdE0HxG8AAAAASUVORK5CYII=\" /></p>",
      "OPT1": "<p>\r\n\t35.7 mm<sup>3</sup>/s</p>",
      "OPT2": "<p>\r\n\t37.7 mm<sup>3</sup>/s</p>",
      "OPT3": "<p>\r\n\t41.7 mm<sup>3</sup>/s</p>",
      "OPT4": "<p>\r\n\t47.7 mm<sup>3</sup>/s</p>",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "9m/iwvJKC6coEJr5HJJczQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "9m/iwvJKC6coEJr5HJJczQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0",
      "OPT2": "\u00a0",
      "OPT3": "\u00a0",
      "OPT4": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13298796",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18438864",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "7",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "MECHANICAL ENGINEERING",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "2.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.66",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu14": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>\r\n\tIn an orthogonal turning operation, it has been observed that the friction force acting on chiptool interface is 402.5 N and acts in the direction normal to the cutting velocity. The feed velocity is negligible as compared to the cutting velocity. The ratio of friction force and normal force is 1. The uncut chip thickness is 0.2 mm and chip thickness is 0.4 mm and the cutting velocity is 2 m/s. The rate of heat generation at the primary shear plane is _______ Watts. (Correct upto 1 decimal place)</p>",
      "OPT1": "402.5 (400.0 - 404.0)",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "yB23yFJ5/CQjRKCRPzIXK0IHRadQbglIc85SxBXyNbc=",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "5kxMa8YwwyHwJY15nzG3sQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13298796",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18438864",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "2",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "Alphanumeric",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "MECHANICAL ENGINEERING",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "2.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.00",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu15": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>\r\n\tA cast iron specimen of 10 mm width and 100 mm length is ground using a A27K6V wheel of 300 mm diameter and 25 mm width. If the wheel has undergone a radial wheel wear of 50 microns after removing a layer of 5 mm, the grinding ratio is ______. (Correct upto 2 decimal places)</p>",
      "OPT1": "4.24 (4.20 - 4.29)",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "0US1vdNqeLGvg/WStUAKo5M4rn+jJ7vgeyP/J/4lWX8=",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "5kxMa8YwwyHwJY15nzG3sQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13298796",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18438864",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "2",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "Alphanumeric",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "MECHANICAL ENGINEERING",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "2.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.00",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu16": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>\r\n\tA bar of length 50 mm and diameter 50 mm is turned to 38 mm diameter using a cutting speed of 450 rpm and feed of 0.2 mm/rev. If the maximum depth of cut is 3 mm and a total allowance of 3 mm is provided then the machining time is ____ minutes. (Correct upto 2 decimal places)</p>",
      "OPT1": "1.18 (1.11 - 1.24)",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "D8wmA0kp6RDtaiAXysjxabdXjdhU/ELNbs7wspvAnNU=",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "5kxMa8YwwyHwJY15nzG3sQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13298796",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18438864",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "2",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "Alphanumeric",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "MECHANICAL ENGINEERING",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "2.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.00",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu17": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>\r\n\tThe figure below shows the tool life curves for tool <em>A</em> and tool <em>B</em>. Both tools follow Taylor\u2019s tool life equation <em>VT<sup>n</sup></em> = <em>c</em>.</p>\r\n<p>\r\n\t<img alt=\"\" src=\"data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAdkAAADrCAYAAAAlguwQAAAgAElEQVR4Xu3df3hV1Z3v8c/M43irE2mlPt5U9IrVlOuPwhSkF5FeoQMVi4VAagGJmoiAIWBCUn4l0YiQIDAJQfmhoiRIEBAJAaVqSQsdFB1jeC7+HEynpaNonEFxaK716cOTe/c+JxtPIJDk5PzYa503/1nP3nut13fZD2vvtff6m//n/BF/EEAAAQQQQCDiAn9DyEbclBMigAACCCAQECBkGQgIIIAAAghESYCQjRIsp0UAAQQQQICQZQwggAACCCAQJQFCNkqwnBYBBBBAAAFCljGAAAIIIIBAlAQI2SjBcloEEEAAAQTCCNkWNTfu06+fX6+isl/py4DhpRqe/0uNuekmjRrwHf2tL13/qqaGXdpU2aSbKrLU/5zTG9nStF8rC+9T+Uv/SxUNK5Sa3M6PfNk3GoUAAggg4EeBLoasE1R7lioz/XUNKMnXXT+/SSlJTqS2fKIDGx9V4bMpemRHplLOlrItH2tv8VTNunCB6vMG6By1njPnfJUcyAuG34kGLe8/X6qs0awBSRFwO6Gm2hwNyt4mfXuOatzr6JRrNNdredocfTZvqx66+r90OOkKfdftG38QQAABBBAIU6BLIdvy8XZlDyuRlmzTqtTL285Y3WDM/XdNXDlWyWdtzIeqnTxeL/xsi55MvcxN1GAAPj9crz/V0bFh9jJwWOt1HrgyGLKnTFJPNJRr4Oh/UzEz2O4gcywCCCCAQIhAF0L27CF18pyts9qS/0zTFnem2uafU/TH2mW6L3ut3g8cMEQ5q8bqszXFqn6n2fnnJPUr2akNN36qmsrNOpZW5sxkW9T4m0oteTZJE294QzMLdzi3qK9X+qoyzUvtoyRvFj1vnXPOJF1992OqXDBcyadNQkPbn6vv/fF3es67Rp/DqsrJ0IMvfRTsRv/F2r1xiI7UONctbD3vXcv0SMGY4MydPwgggAACCHRCoAsh+5UaqzI1onxguzPB4GTRvQU7Sis+ky7M36X6+6RHQ/85cHu4g5ls03bdMyBLdeqrnJ0VumL1L5T70lEnf8fowZ3LlJFyTLVZacp97XanHdN1QbXTpk2DVLNtpv7h+A5npp2lF928doOyza3rkJDddYVWD/KuEbwl3XYm+4X2FtymJRct1da8gUoK3ErO1N6J27Q9o49Pnzl3otr8BAEEEEAgpgJdCNkWHd9TrEH3SqvrF2hojzPN6NwQvUULrl3f+sy1vX/u4HZxIGjX6NqdbgBKB8rHady7Wa23k0NnpHfq+AOjldEwPhCygeesaRP19M1bWq8dannKTPxo6DVOCdnz96lo4ERVu2Ed8ifwF4fAXxT4gwACCCCAQMcCXQhZ52TH9zjhM0UN0zYFZ3jtnr+DkG05pKoxk/TK5O2tz2RbZ8j7fvH1M9lOh6x723eHHp4x++Tt5qvvWqCS+25T/+RzT2ldF0JWzzshv0zJ1Tu1aNhFHSvyCwQQQAABBNoR6FrIeiuB06ukuwo1NzNNQ1N6BE7b0tSgXfXSwFEX6/Upt6jgnIWqWzNGPRqrlTt6jhPMrbPAwC3l8dqbt6v11mtzcKa6Z+LJ27stjZUaO3SThobOZE/++1PC8qtDqi19Sl9kPuTcSv7GWYrc9rh/+GPoNbyZbL1y9lYq48pPg7ekD9+iipWzlZqS5Ly2VK8PLvhBO+HNuEIAAQQQQKB9gS6GbCBOz/Ce7Byl/2ykE7rSoarZGhtYoOS8P/vQLF1bW6wVB5x7ryPXOLPVUVLgNaCVev+6+cFnqc2/1YK77tX6d65zFkLdonezi51nsu38Cbx+0/octnCP84M0lVX31dPpxTrY5ueDnOe5Vc6t5m+1/q8hr/Ccdtq+ysq/XpvL1ulY4N+5z4JrlNPrfW18ZIHuX/+m8785C60eLtaMSQPbWVDF0EIAAQQQQCBiIesnSvcDE1u1pvYCTVswWpe4j4kDi5TO9FzWT22nLQgggAACtguEMZP1EUngGfFMNS15sfX5rjvRdp/5pml7GiuBfVQpmoIAAggkpIDZIRsI1FFaevED2r4iXX2SmoO3qhf/N5Xu+SelXnLq4qeErDGdRgABBBCIk4DZIRt4PlyntQ8XaEXgQxLOxyhOWZAVJ1cuiwACCCCAgAwPWSqIAAIIIICAfwUIWf/WhpYhgAACCBguQMgaXkCajwACCCDgXwFC1r+1oWUIIIAAAoYLELKGF5DmI4AAAgj4V8CYkO3dK1mHjzT5V5KWIYAAAgggcIqAESHrBqz3h6BlDCOAAAIImCJAyJpSKdqJAAIIIGCcACFrXMloMAIIIICAKQKErCmVop0IIIAAAsYJELLGlYwGI4AAAgiYIuD7kA1d9OShsvjJlOFFOxFAAIHEFiBkE7v+9B4BBBBAIIoChGwUcTk1AggggEBiC/g+ZL3y8DGKxB6o9B4BBBAwUYCQNbFqtBkBBBBAwAgBQtaIMtFIBBBAAAETBQhZE6tGmxFAAAEEjBAgZI0oE41EAAEEEDBRgJA1sWq0GQEEEEDACAFC1ogy0UgEEEAAARMFCFkTq0abEUAAAQSMECBkjSgTjUQAAQQQMFGAkDWxarQZAQQQQMAIAULWiDLRSAQQQAABEwUIWROrRpsRQAABBIwQIGSNKBONRAABBBAwUYCQNbFqtBkBBBBAwAgBQtaIMp25kQcPHtR//sd/aPiIEYb3hOYjgAAC9gkQsobXtLGxUcvLy7R6zWOG94TmI4AAAvYJELKG1/Qvf/mLrr7qCh0+0mR4T2g+AgggYJ8AIWtBTadn3atZeflKSUmxoDd0AQEEELBHgJC1oJbV1Rv05z//WVlZ0y3oDV1AAAEE7BEgZC2o5eeff65xY0brxV/v1nnnnWdBj+gCAgggYIcAIWtHHeXeMr7jjjt1w+DBlvSIbiCAAALmCxCy5tcw0IPX9u/Xhg1Ps8rYknrSDQQQsEOAkLWjjnJXGd/ykxGq2bFTPXv2tKRXdAMBBBAwW4CQNbt+bVq/Zs1qXXDBBUpPv8OiXtEVBBBAwFwBQtbc2p3W8iNHPtKkCRO0d98rFvWKriCAAALmChCy5tau3ZazAMqygtIdBBAwWoCQNbp8pze+bvduHTjQoDlz51nWM7qDAAIImCdAyJpXs7O22PvM4oG332MBlGW1pTsIIGCeACFrXs06bLG7ACrlqhR25ulQih8ggAAC0RUgZKPrG5ezu9vflS5aqC1bn4vL9bkoAggggEBQgJC1dCSMv+3nKq+oUK9el1raQ7qFAAII+F+AkPV/jcJqIZsGhMXGQQgggEBEBQjZiHL652RsGuCfWtASBBBIXAFCNszaFxbM1/TsbF/fjuULUGEWl8MQQACBCAkQsmFCurdj3T9+/oShO5vt//1rxOs8YRaZwxBAAIFuChCyYQI2NjaqyJnN+n0Frzubdf+woXuYheYwBBBAoBsChGw38ExYwctsthsF5lAEEECgmwKEbDcATbhl7Havtna7PvnkE2az3ag1hyKAAALhCBCy4ai1HuPuepOXm+v7W8beXrNr11UqJSWlGz3mUAQQQACBrggQsl3Raue37i3jgqL71a9fv26eKbqHu7PZ+jfeUEnp4uheiLMjgAACCJwUIGS7ORhMuRXLbLabheZwBBBAIAwBQjYMtNBDTProA7PZbhabwxFAAIEuChCyXQRr7+fuhyluvfVnumHw4AicLXqnYDYbPVvOjAACCLQnQMhGYFy8tn+/Nmx4WqvXPBaBs0X3FMxmo+vL2RFAAIFQAUI2QuNh6I+GaOPmzb7+zKLbVWazESo4p0EAAQQ6IUDIdgKpMz8xadcbZrOdqSi/QQABBLovQMh23zBwBpMWQDGbjVDROQ0CCCDQgQAhG8EhYsoCKLfLzGYjWHhOhQACCJxBgJCN4NA4ePCgShct9P0XoNwuu7PZjDvvMOJDGhEsEadCAAEEYipAyEaY25QvQLnd9v5SUPX0Bp133nkRluB0CCCAAAKEbITHQN3u3dqz57fGfL7QvcV99TXX+Hpf3AiXiNMhgAACMRMgZCNM7S0qMuF1Hrfr3lZ4r77xpu9fP4pwqTgdAgggEHUBQjYKxKZ8z9jrutveX7/8shEf04hCuTglAgggEDUBQjYKtCZulO4+S54ydZqGjxgRBRFOiQACCCSmACEbpbqvWbM6cOasrOlRukJkT9vY2Kgpd2eqZsdO9ezZM7In52wIIIBAggoQslEqvImzWferVe+/954xi7aiVDpOiwACCERMgJCNGOXpJzJtNuu9O8tt4ygOCk6NAAIJJUDIRrHcJs5muW0cxQHBqRFAIOEECNkol9y02azLwW3jKA8KTo8AAgkjQMhGudQmzma5bRzlQcHpEUAgYQQI2RiU2sTZ7JEjH2nShAlG7JEbgxJyCQQQQCAsAUI2LLauHWTibNbtIR+p6Fqd+TUCCCBwqgAhG6Mx4QbWB4cOac7ceTG6YmQuMz3rXg2+8Ua+bRwZTs6CAAIJJkDIxqjgpm6U7m1Gv3ZdpVJSUmKkxWUQQAABOwQI2RjW0dSN0l/bv1/z587Ri7/ezZZ4MRwvXAoBBMwXIGRjXEP3G8G5s/J0w+DBMb5y9y7nLt766MMP+RpU9xg5GgEEEkyAkI1xwU3dKN293Z2fN0s/uflmpaaOjbEal0MAAQTMFCBk41A3d6P0gT/8oXFh5b3Ww/PZOAwaLokAAkYKELJxKJsbVjf+8HodePs943a84flsHAYMl0QAAWMFCNk4lc7kTxe6z2fffustNnmP09jhsgggYI4AIRunWnmv9KxYuUr9+vWLUyvCv6z7/uz3+/Y1Zr/c8HvKkQgggED4AoRs+HbdPtLURVBux72/JCxestS4ldLdLhwnQAABBDopQMh2EipaP3MXQV19zTVGflHJe7b86htvqlevS6NFxHkRQAABYwUI2TiXzvui0sbNm40MKhZCxXkAcXkEEPC1ACHrg/KY/iF+byFUWflyvgjlg/FEExBAwD8ChKxPauEuJDL5Qw/ube9LL7uMhVA+GU80AwEE/CFAyPqjDjL9+ab3RSh27PHJgKIZCCDgCwFC1hdlCDbC9NvG3hehWHHso0FFUxBAIK4ChGxc+U+/uOm3jQlanw0omoMAAnEVIGTjyn/6xb2QMnW1sdsj9/3fnBnZMrkPPhsWNAcBBAwVIGR9WLi63bu19onHVfX0BmNX63qv9hC0PhxgNAkBBGImQMjGjLprF7JhtS5B27Wa82sEELBPgJD1aU1N/7axx+q+Q7vlmWe4dezTcUazEEAgugKEbHR9u3V279lmzY6dxm2JF9pxPlbRrWHAwQggYLAAIevz4rlb4u1/9VXjt5UjaH0+0GgeAghERYCQjQprZE/qvtZjw0ce3OfM3/zmNzVn7rzIAnE2BBBAwKcChKxPCxPaLG8TAVP3nvX64n0Vin1oDRh0NBEBBCIiQMhGhDH6J7Hl3VM3aDPuvEMTJ01SaurY6MNxBQQQQCCOAoRsHPG7emnv+azpu93wVaiuVp7fI4CAqQKErGGVs+H9WZecoDVs4NFcBBAIS4CQDYstfgd5t1unTJ2m4SNGxK8hEbgyQRsBRE6BAAK+FiBkfV2e9hvnhdPadZVKSUkxsAdfN5mgNbp8NB4BBDoQIGQNHSI2fbKQoDV0ENJsBBDoUICQ7ZDIvz/w9p81fSGUK+wFbdEDxcbfBvfviKFlCCAQawFCNtbiEb6e+yWljz78UCWliyN85tifzgva8bffrqys6bFvAFdEAAEEIixAyEYYNNans+0DD27QlixaJD5YEeuRxPUQQCAaAoRsNFRjfE6bVhy7dN5fHHr37q2Z9+UYu6dujIcBl0MAAR8KELI+LEo4TbJt8ZAbtIsWPqRjx47JhmfO4dSUYxBAwHwBQtb8Gp7sQWNjo0YM/ZF2791n/Ks9Xqe83XsKi4rUq9elFlWLriCAQCIIELKWVdmmV3u80rirqCvKytj43bKxSncQSAQBQtbCKtsYtG6fJt42Tpu21uiGwYMtrBpdQgABGwUIWRur6vTJxk3S3dvhU+7OVG5+Pjv4WDpu6RYCtgkQsrZVNKQ/NgZt6Cs+GRmZrDy2ePzSNQRsECBkbajiWfpgY9B6r/i43WblseUDmO4hYLgAIWt4ATvTfBuD1u23268tzzzDgqjODAJ+gwACcREgZOPCHtuL2jzzq9u9W4seWqDFS5ayICq2w4qrIYBAJwQI2U4g2fATm4P24MGDypmRzYIoGwYqfUDAMgFC1rKCnq07tn3nOLSv7oKovNxcDf3xj8WCqAQa1HQVAZ8LELI+L1Ckm2fzjNbmvkV6HHA+BBCIjQAhGxtnX13F9jDyFkStXVdpzeclfTWAaAwCCHRagJDtNJVdP7Q9aL2vXt0zbZrS0++wq3j0BgEEjBEgZI0pVeQb6gZtVVWl3n7rLSvfN/38889VVFgQgFtUUqqePXtGHpEzIoAAAmcRIGQZHlZ+gjG0rNXVG/Tk44/zmg9jHQEEYi5AyMac3J8X9D5YYeuMz/vu8U9vvZWN4P05BGkVAlYKELJWljW8Ttn+BSX39vijj6xQw5tvalHpYhZFhTdMOAoBBLogQMh2ASsRfup9QWnj5s3WbpLu9dFdFJWW9nM2GUiEgU0fEYiTACEbJ3g/X9ZbmWvzpwrdRVFl/7RMv3e2zyuvqLD2LxR+Hme0DYFEECBkE6HKYfTR+1ShzUHrsnizWvaoDWOQcAgCCHQoQMh2SJS4P3A/VThpwgSNv/12ZWVNtxbC26PW7WBhURGzWmsrTccQiL0AIRt7c6Ou6L1r+v2+fa3/JnBt7XblZmfpyaoNGj5ihFF1orEIIOBPAULWn3XxVavcVbmLFj6kY8eOWfnRilBsb6OBq1JSlP/L2XzAwlcjkcYgYJ4AIWtezeLWYttf8fFg3b9UbNv2XOADFitWrlK/fv3iZs6FEUDAbAFC1uz6xbz1ibRJurf4iw9YxHyYcUEErBEgZK0pZew6kkibpPMBi9iNK66EgI0ChKyNVY1Bn7wVub17906IzxR6M/gbf/QjntXGYHxxCQRsESBkbalkHPrhzfIOHz6cEK++uP19+eWXVFFWFnitafz4CSyMisO445IImCRAyJpULZ+21X31xQ2eRFkk5L7WtGXLZm155hm5H7G4+eaRfJrRp2OTZiEQbwFCNt4VsOT63nPaRNok3fs046v79qnogWLerbVkLNMNBCIpQMhGUjPBzxW6SXpZ+fKEmd252+hVVa4LfAe5oOh+XvlJ8P8O6D4CoQKELOMh4gLe+7Rr11Um1HZy7sYKFcvL5X7IIiPz7oTqe8QHESdEwBIBQtaSQvqtG95OPol0+9itAYuj/DYSaQ8C8RUgZOPrb/XVQ28fLyopTaiVuCyOsnpo0zkEOi1AyHaaih+GK1BdvSFhP1Hovk+8etWqwPPa3Fl5umHw4HAZOQ4BBAwUIGQNLJqJTXYXB025OzPwfmlGRmbCLIryauWuvn7Wee2npHRxF8v3hQ6UZyj9aI5eLx2mHl08mp8jgEB8BQjZ+Pon1NX5RGFXy92i5obVmlmwTf9y7p3asSNTKX/b1XPwewQQiKcAIRtP/QS9tveJwkRbFNXlcjfXa3nOv+imhf9TNcO26/rfrVBq8jldPg0HIIBA/AQI2fjZJ/SVvQ85uHvUFhYVqVevSxPa4/TO/1Uf11boucum6r4ffKqqMffq93lbtWjYRTghgIBBAoSsQcWysanuJxlzs7NUsWqNUlPH2tjFsPrU8vF2ZQ/L0ovN3uFJ6leyS9sz+og7xmGRchACcREgZOPCzkVDBbwdfdz/jVmtg9DyJ9UWv6T/MXeK+ie5kfqVGqsyNeaDqSx+4j8dBAwTIGQNK5jNzQ2d1SbuR/fd28QParGmaUXq5SdnrScayjUwU3rqQJ7681jW5v8M6JtlAoSsZQU1vTves1r3vdJFzusuKc4nChPpT+A28cgDGv/KAg3tEXJjuGm77hnwrIbsrVRGyjcSiYS+ImC0ACFrdPnsbby3Ajmh3qsNBGmW6tyyfnuOalpnrYFZ7OilOhYod5oqGlhlbO/Ip2e2CRCytlXUov5479X+6oUXtHjJUr6WZFFt6QoCiSJAyCZKpQ3up/u1qKKC+YHdbaZnZ/O6j8G1pOkIJJoAIZtoFTe0v97uNt7rPom7MMrQAtJsBBJUgJBN0MKb2m1vYdSr+/ZxC9nUItJuBBJIgJBNoGLb1FX3g/ulixayQbpNRaUvCFgoQMhaWNRE6pL7bm1FWVlgd5/x4yck1J61iVRn+oqAqQKErKmVo90nBdggncGAAAJ+FSBk/VoZ2tVlAW+DdJ7XdpmOAxBAIEoChGyUYDlt/AS8V37cFhQU3a9+/frFrzFcGQEEElqAkE3o8tvd+df271fF8nJNmTpNw0eM6KCzzTpQPk7jyt5q87vzRxZrfclkDUw+124seocAAlERIGSjwspJzRQ4oabaHA166nrt3pGplC+dTdPTsvRu1nY9mXqZmV2i1QggEFcBQjau/FzcXwLB2exkZw+c+rwBOkdHtbfgHtWNeJLN0v1VKFqDgDEChKwxpaKh0Rf4ULWTJ+vN9GecUD1XjbWrtP5PN2nGzMFKZqf06PNzBQQsFCBkLSwqXQpT4ESDlvcfpRWfuccn6eq75mt62k81asB3Tu7rGuaZOQwBBBJUgJBN0MLT7dMFWhorNfbWP2hWvbuXq9R8qFq5o1/UkBfYw5XxggAC4QkQsuG5cZR1Ai06vqdYg8q/qx3uoif39nBgZjtfqqzRrAFJ1vWYDiGAQPQFCNnoG3MFIwS+UmNVpkbs+4Vef2qsknXceSa7TL98sb/WrBmrS3gma0QVaSQCfhMgZP1WEdoTB4HWWWz6Wn158uqXanh+qeZOHa6UJBI2DkXhkghYIUDIWlFGOoEAAggg4EcBQtaPVaFNCCCAAAJWCBCyVpSRTiCAAAII+FGAkPVjVWgTAggggIAVAoSsFWWkEwgggAACfhQgZP1YFdqEAAIIIGCFACFrRRnpBAIIIICAHwUIWT9WhTYhgAACCFghQMhaUUY6gQACnRJobtTel59XdcFS1TUHjzh/5BwtSr1Jg0cNYLelNogtam6s09qH63RFSalSk8/pFDE/aitAyDIiEEAgIQRamuq04K5cvTEgX3Mz0zQ0xdkFQn9VU8NWrSx4WVetfEIZKd84i4Xz2z1LlZlzvkoO5Km/kznBc1boW6WbW79vfeqexKbSnlBTbY4GZW9zNqSaoqrAphl8+SycahKy4ahxDAIImCXQ8ifVZqWpQIWqO+1b1G4wlunfby/sYLbWGjzPD2/9vrVD0LRd9wyo060NKyyc6bX294ErVdP6lwqziu6P1hKy/qgDrUAAgQ4EevdKPu0Xh480dc4tEIZrdO3Os++o1NJUr42PPKmjaWWBmenX/7xMU3r8Rg/PmK3qd9z7zEnql79Ydx5dr/z1bwbb0H+xdm8coiM1lXr08zRtyfuBvgrcbn1ZF95+jV6Z7gR8s7tP8TI9UjDG+Sa2E2KBWXRx8JzXzVDV+jkamnzuKX1yZtD1T6kofUHgFvf5I+fr0XmZ+scr/68O7Nykyj9crtHHKjVlnduO65W+qkzzUvsoyb01/lyllhSu0/uB/ZG96zarcc82rX+4pPW6U1SxcrZS3Zl9yyeBc66e695O76vhI6W6+pGEbOdGWbu/6nTItjfAu3FdDkUAAQQiKnC2wA3sFTx0k4aeJWRPNJRr4OilOqa+ynF+N1NPtPnnWQO+EbyFesaZ7CeqnXyLcl86qgvzd+j57z6tIe7tVjmbTZRUqSLjezpe+0sNz/5XTXHOn9Njq9OmHU6bqjTrB/8VmGnnvvCR8/thenBvyB7GLYdUNeZe/T5vqxYN66GPaxfq8b8fpG/lT9aKz5yfe+F88Weqf7RQdy39i+bsXabelXdoyUVLtTVvoBO49Vqelqm9E5/V+ss3afDDF6l620z1TzruzOIzNG7PGO3e/mO9mz1Rj1/8kCoXDFfyl4dUW5rvtOnHhGw3Rioh2w08DkUAAX8JnDFoj+9R0cBC6bGdTlBddOZGnzrjbfPPHYWsuzDow0DQLrh2verzBkiB4P43FXu3k0+e7zlNPr5Mg9LfdgLXCVnnp4Gwq/rf7QTaF86/m6rCozdr2g97St+8TsOHpSgpEL6jtGLYlsC1AsuSAv2cqabZM5W8zJkhty7u8jp8Yf5TWnq0RFPW/6GtwbfnqGbXFVo9KHS2z+3iSIzuTodsJC7WnXO4M+lO3xrqzoU4FgEEfClwprtpnfv/haPaWzBaGQ3jVROYwZ1hEc9ZQ/acU/Ycdu6uBmbIbyrz5DPZzoasc9u6z5HgTNG73Xzd3VpYOlOTBnxH7bbOvZW7a7/eeq1SS5Wv10uv0m9DAv3rkH1CVz12q15JX6Xk6lP/UhFsX8F/f9Q5fpjcpV/en9Nn+4RsJP5DIGQjocg5EEAg6gKhIdu5YG3bpOBK4Hu1Xr/Qg84zzZ+7s0H3J4Hw+j/SwH9Uf+1ynt2W6O9WbdOq1AudUJ2tsYV/DNzeDc42xzm3Vidq945MpThJGLzFXK8c7/buKbPL4Ew25N+3CfEWNdYuV/kXE7Qqo0/7weq270SDlt/+lm7d7F7zuA45bZrwwQT9rjVkC5St9SWTNfBi5y8SxdO1RDNUWZyi17Od28+Hb2l93prkvI5Trw8uuFbJrxc4t6z/oHEhz27/+VCShvT5SCvSJmrtpQ9o+4p09dF7qsrJ0IOv3MLq4m6MbkK2G3gcigAChgmc6T3Z9J/pJ27oNr8TDJaXnGejSWP0QOmV2nFfuQ7qIg1f9aKeGHQoGNTvXOc8t3WfpX7pBNtUZaz7V12dv1Dj3y1xjj3aDkrwOW/wOez84PkeWaYhVTP14IHQe7rOAqX8TcHnqCenmJ+0Pmv9lb50/rfzRxYHQzX50+Cs9KNL1Oudt9SY9I7JVUgAAAIXSURBVFPlVZdoxsDgTDi4aGuB7g/MlJ0FUQ8Xa8akgUqW85eKjY+qcJ63IGqBSu67Tf2d92CbG3e0Lu6Ss1CqVHO/9xtlFO6Q3NvJrDAOa7ATsmGxcRACCCDQPYFACK6q0wVZ+Uq9xF1R7D57PdNz2fau1fbWNJ+K6F49onU0IRstWc6LAAIInFGg9Rnxp7O/fudWXwWf+W77ycnb0WcHJGRNGGCErAlVoo0IIGCZQGugLu6hB3cuU0Yf55npoWrljn5Ef7fEfR58+Zmf0Z68jRxcXbz0+2tPW8RkGZbR3SFkjS4fjUcAAWMFnOfDv3lisWaWBZ+1ylld3GZB1tk65i6G6u+8vuO+J+v8uTB/19ev8RgLYmfDCVk760qvEEAAAQR8IEDI+qAINAEBBBBAwE4BQtbOutIrBBBAAAEfCBCyPigCTUAAAQQQsFOAkLWzrvQKAQQQQMAHAoSsD4pAExBAAAEE7BQgZO2sK71CAAEEEPCBACHrgyLQBAQQQAABOwUIWTvrSq8QQAABBHwgQMj6oAg0AQEEEEDATgFC1s660isEEEAAAR8IELI+KAJNQAABBBCwU4CQtbOu9AoBBBBAwAcChKwPikATEEAAAQTsFCBk7awrvUIAAQQQ8IEAIeuDItAEBBBAAAE7BQhZO+tKrxBAAAEEfCBAyPqgCDQBAQQQQMBOAULWzrrSKwQQQAABHwj8f6X+nT+ZjnXfAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\" /></p>\r\n<p>\r\n\tWhich of the following statement(s) is/are correct regarding these tools?</p>",
      "OPT1": "<p>\r\n\tValue of <em>n</em> for both the tools is same.</p>\r\n",
      "OPT2": "<p>\r\n\tValue of <em>c</em> for both the tools is same.</p>\r\n",
      "OPT3": "<p>\r\n\tValue of <em>c</em> for tool <em>A</em> is greater than that for tool <em>B</em>.</p>\r\n",
      "OPT4": "<p>\r\n\tValue of <em>c</em> for tool <em>B</em> is greater than that for tool <em>A</em>.</p>\r\n",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "kANto1cr89QZ3IzSaugRPA==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "kANto1cr89QZ3IzSaugRPA==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0",
      "OPT2": "\u00a0",
      "OPT3": "\u00a0",
      "OPT4": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13298796",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18438864",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "5",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "MECHANICAL ENGINEERING",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "2.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.00",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "TEST_NAME": "Discovered Test 6464538",
  "TEST_ID_ENCODED": "NjQ2NDUzOA==",
  "TEST_ID": "NjQ2NDUzOA=="
}